Guide to the Guerrilla Girls Archive, 1985-2015 MSS.274
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series V: Posters and Graphic Works 1985-2010
  - Subseries B: Postcards, Stickers, and Miscellaneous Graphic Works
    - "Where to Get an Abortion in Buffalo" Brochures, undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Photos of GG W/ Dead Women Artists Pictures, undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Photos of [_____] in Mask, undated (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Gender Postcard 2000 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Cards and Stickers, circa 1987-2015 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - "Provoke, Protest, and Prevail" Patches, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - "Provoke, Protest, Prevail" Temporary Tattoos, circa 2003 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - "Provoke, Protest, Prevail" Armbands, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - "Know Your Theatre Lingo" Cards, circa 1999 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - "What Do Toilet Stalls and the Tony Awards Have in Common?" Cards, circa 1998 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Giuliani "Welcome to New York" Flyer, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Letters to Bad Bosses Stickers, circa 2001 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Guerrilla Girls Talk Back: Falkirk Cultural Center Retrospective, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - "Dear Theatre Producer" Cards to Neil Pepe, circa 1987-2015 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - "GGBB Wear" Brochure, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - "Cartographies of Choice" Card and Brochure, 2010 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - New Observations, #70, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - "Heads of State", 2011 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - "Heads of State", The Brooklyn Rail, 2015 June (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Subseries C: Dimensional Works and Ephemera
    - Yellow Foam Banana, undated (Box 6, Object ID: 274.2.0001, Box 10)
    - "I'm a Guerrilla Girl" pins, undated (Box 6, Object ID: 274.2.0002)
    - GGBB "Protest--Prevail--Provoke" patches, undated (Box 6, Object ID: 274.2.0003)
    - Guerrilla Girls pencils, undated (Box 6, Object ID: 274.2.0004)
    - Guerrilla Girls "Spy Mission" Kit [1 of 2], undated (Box 6, Object ID: 274.2.0005)
    - Guerrilla Girls "Spy Mission" Kit [2 of 2], undated (Box 6, Object ID: 274.2.0006)
    - "Prevail, Provoke, Protest" Shirt, circa 2003 (Box 10)
    - Mousepad: "Think Gender Doesn't Matter in the New Economy?", 2001 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Series VI: Publications 1985-1998
  Series VI comprises works authored and compiled by the Guerrilla Girls, along with annotated proofs and drafts.
  Subseries A. Publications
  Subseries B. Proofs and Notes
  - Subseries A: Publications
    - Guerrilla Girls: The Banana Report, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - New Observations, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Guerrilla Girls Talk Back, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - GG Bedside Companion to History of Western Art, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Subseries B: Proofs and Notes
    - Notes for "Bedside Companion", 1997 (Box 5, Folder 37)
- Series VII: Media, 1997-2008
  Conditions Governing Access
  Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
  Scope and Contents
  Ccontains research materials, administrative records and legal documentation.
  - Subseries A: Originals, 1997-2008
    - "Trouble" festival Belgium 04/08--Tracy Essoglou Trevisa, Italy Photo CD, April 2008 (Box 9, Media ID: 274.0001)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
      Original format: 4.5" Photo CD compatible with Windows 95/98/ME/2000/XP
      Currently unavailable until duplication occurs.
      General Note
      This media is associated with "Old and New Members [2 of 2]" folder: Series I, Subseries B, Box 1, Folder 28.
    - "Cigarettes, Reading, Masturbation and boys" film by Diane Torr, undated (Box 9, Media ID: 274.0002)
      4.5" DVD
      General
    - "Women Art Revolution" DVD, 2007 (Box 9, Media ID: 274.0003)
      General note
      This media is associated with "Lynn Hershman: Women, Art, Revolution" folder: Series I, Subseries B, Box 2, Folder 12.
    - Financials--GG 2/10/08-7/7/97, 1997 (Box 9, Media ID: 274.0004)
      3.5" computer floppy disk
      This media is associated with "GG Bookkeeping Runs '97" folder: Series I, Subseries C, Box 2, Folder 21. Media separated from "Lynn Hershman: Women, Art, Revolution" folder: Series I, Subseries B, Box 2, Folder 12.
    - Guerrilla Girls Accounting 1999 disk (Box 9, Media ID: 274.0005)
      This media is associated with "Accounting Info 99 [1 of 4]" folder: Series I, Subseries C, Box 2, Folder 30.
    - GG Quicken Backup disk, 1999 (Box 9, Media ID: 274.0006)
    - AR 97B--GG disk, 1999 (Box 9, Media ID: 274.0007)
    - Alma Thomas declaration, 2004 (Box 9, Media ID: 274.0008)
      4.5" CD-R
      This media is associated with "GG Legal Decision Documentation: June 2005 [3 of 3]" folder: Series II, Subseries A, Box 4, Folder 5.
    - Guerrilla Girls BroadBand recorded by Creative Time @ Armory "Democracy in America" video 10/24/08, 2008; 274.0009 (Box 9, Media ID: 274.0009, E-records fales_mss274, E-records FA_MSS_274_1)
      4.5" DVD-R
      This media is associated with "Creative Time/Democracy in Action" folder: Series III, Subseries A, Box 5, Folder 2.
    - Counter-recruit card for Democracy in Action 9/27/08, 2008 (Box 9, Media ID: 274.0010)
    - GGBB at the beach-09/08, 2008 (Box 9, Media ID: 274.0011, E-records fales_mss274, E-records FA_MSS_274_2)
    - Uncle Sam Counter-Recruitment Posters--English and Spanish, May 17, 2008, Bronx Museum (Box 9, Media ID: 274.0012)
    - GGBB Music--9/24/08 Democracy in Action, 2008-09-24 (Box 9, Media ID: 274.0013, E-records fales_mss274, E-records FA_MSS_274_3)
    - John McCain on SNL 11/1/08, 2008 (Box 9, Media ID: 274.0014)
      4.5" DVD-RW
    - Tina Fey as Sarah Palin on SNL 9/13/08, 2008 (Box 9, Media ID: 274.0015)
    - Media-related Documentation and Enclosures, 2007-2008 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Series VIII: Archived Websites, September 2007-ongoing; 7 websites in 7 archived websites.
  Accruals
  New site crawls are accrued quarterly and semiannually.
  Appraisal
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored with the permission of the content owner.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of guerrillagirls.com, guerrillagirlsbroadband.com, and guerrillagirlsontour.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Google Map, Google Sheet, and Youtube video were added to better capture embedded elements in the website but were not individually added to the finding aid.
  This series contains the websites for the three separate Guerrilla Girls groups formed after 2000, Guerrilla Girls, Inc., Guerrilla Girls On Tour, Inc., and GuerrillaGirlsBroadBand, Inc. These websites contain information on their upcoming lectures, book signings, performances, and workshops. They also contain summaries of performances and books, where their art is being exhibited, biographies of women artists that become the members' pseudonyms, videos of their performances, Guerrilla Girls printable mask, posters, current and past projects, and press. Editions of their newsletter go back to 2001. Topics focused on the website include lack of women and people of color in the film industry and art museums; abortion; hate speech; war; and marriage equality. In 2016, http://www.guerrillagirls.com/ was redesigned.
  The Male Graze was an online art commission by the Guerrilla Girls, Inc. for Art Night 2021, a contemporary art festival in the United Kingdom. The Male Graze explores western art's focus on female bodies, male artists exploitation and abuse of women, rewriting of museum wall labels to reflect these exploitation and abuse, and naked women versus women artists counts at reported museums. The website is broken down into six sections: Flesh Through the Ages, Bad Male Behavior, Art School/Art World Confidential, Helping Museums Write Wall Labels, Are There More Naked Women Than Women Artists in Museums?, and Comments/Apologies.
  Capture of Guerrilla Girls On Tour, Inc. began in 2019. Guerrilla Girls on Tour is the blog listing their upcoming lectures, book signings, performances, and workshops for the Guerrilla Girls. The website was redesigned in 2020 to include more information on their books, UN/MASKED and PUSH/PUSHBACK. It also included information on virtual tours during the COVID-19 pandemic. The website redesigned again in 2022.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
- OVERSIZE Series III, V, VI
  - Series III, Subseries B: Lectures, Performances, and Exhibitions Posters
    - "What Does She Want?" Catalog from First Bank Collection Exhibition, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Free Corporation Paper/SUNY Buffalo, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - UCLA Art & Activism Gig Poster, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - "Making it Together" Publication from the Bronx Museum, 2008 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Series V, Subseries A - C: Posters and Graphic Works 1985 - 2010
    - "Hormone Imbalance, Melanin Deficiency" Poster (copies), 1993 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - GGBB Counter-Recruiting Reserves Poster, 2010 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - GGBB Title VII/Bloomberg/Herstory Signage, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Guerrilla Girl Paper Bag Masks, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - WAC-GG Action at Guggenheim (Bag), undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - "3 White Women, 1 Woman of Color and No Men of Color--out of 71 Artists?" Poster, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - "Advantages of Another Bush Presidency" poster, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - "Advantages of Being a Woman Artist" poster, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - "At Last! Museums will no longer discriminate..." poster, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - "Bus Companies are More Enlightened than NYC Art Galleries" poster, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - "Dearest Art Collector..." poster, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - "Did She Risk her life for Governments that Enslave Women" poster, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - "Do women have to be naked to get into the Met. Museum?" poster, undated (Folder 4)
    - "Election Year Lottery" poster, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - "George Bush, the Education President" poster, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - "Guerrilla Girls' 1986 Report Card" poster (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - "Guerrilla Girls' Code of Ethics for Art Museums" poster, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - "Guerrilla Girls' Definition of a Hypocrite" poster, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - "Guerrilla Girls Explain the Concept of Natural Law" poster, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - "Guerrilla Girls Hits List" poster, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - "Guerrilla Girls' Identities Exposed!" poster, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - "Guerrilla Girls Review the Whitney" poster, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - "Guerrilla Girls Urge Drastic N.E.A. Cuts" poster, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - "Hidden Agendas, Passing the Bucks" poster, undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - "Hold on to Your Wallets! Cross Your Legs!" poster, undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - "How Many Women Had One-Person Exhibitions..." poster, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - "It's Even Worse in Europe" poster, undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - "John Russell Thinks Things are Getting Better..." posters, undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - "Montgomery, Alabama 1955?" posters, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - "National Health Care (Missing in Action)" poster, undated (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - "Oh! The Joys of Being a Woman Playwright!" poster, undated (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - "Only 4 Commercial Galleries in N.Y. Show Black Women" poster, undated (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - "Pop's Quiz" poster, undated (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - "Q: How Many Works by Woman Artists...At Sotheby's" poster, undated (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - "Q: What's the Difference Between a Prisoner of War and a Homeless Person?" poster, undated (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - "Relax Senator Helms" poster, undated (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - "These Galleries Show No More Than 10% Women Artists..." poster, undated (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - "Under Surveillance This Year" poster, undated (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - "We Sell White Bread" poster, undated (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - "What Do These Artists Have in Common..." poster, undated (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - "What Do These Men Have in Common?" Andre/Simpson poster, undated (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - "What's Fashionable, Prestigious, & Tax-Deductible?" poster, undated (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - "When Racism & Sexism Are No Longer Fashionable..." poster, undated (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - "Which Art Mag was Worst for Women Last Year?" poster, undated (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - "You're Seeing Less than Half the Picture" poster, undated (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - "Women in America Earn Only 2/3 of What Men Do" poster, undated (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Series VI, Subseries A - B: Publications 1985 - 1998
    - Proof for "Confessions of the Guerrilla Girls", 1994 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Hot Flashes, 1993-1994 (Box 8, Folder 42)